Martin Kamin Papers
Martin Kamin Papers
1789-1973
Kamin, Martin.
25 linear ft.
Papers of the Polish-American publisher and bookseller, primarily in the areas of dance and drama. Collection includes autographs, correspondence, photographs, printed material, and miscellaneous papers.
149095
Biographical History
Martin Kamin (1897 or 1899-1976) was a Polish-American publisher and bookseller, particularly in the areas of dance and drama.
Born on November 15, 1897 (or 1899) in Warsaw, Poland, Kamin left Poland to come to the United States while still in his teens. After mastering English he enrolled at the University of Baltimore and continued his studies in linguistics, philosophy and economics at the University of Geneva in Switzerland where he earned his Ph.D.
In 1920 Kamin married Sarah (Sally) Katz, a school teacher from Milwaukee, Wisconsin. For a number of years she had been associated with the Wisconsin Players as a dramatic actress and dancer performing under the name Sara Nikov. The Kamins resided in Paris during the 1920's and 1930's where Martin began his publishing career. He published Contact: A Quarterly Review (edited by William Carlos Williams and Nathaniel West), Both Sides, Films, and Current Controversy. The Kamins became a part of the "lost generation" which included Hemingway, Fitzgerald and Gertrude Stein. His address book from that period registers the names Aaron Copland, Gustav Holst, Darius Milhaud, Serge Prokofieff, Ralph Vaughan Williams, Picasso, and more.
In addition to his publishing business Kamin operated a book store in New York City which eventually specialized in materials on the dance. For many years the Kamin Dance Book Shop was an internationally known center for books and manuscripts relating to all aspects of that art.
After his wife's death and his retirement Kamin married briefly for a second time, but spent most of his later years weakened by a stroke and living in virtual poverty in various nursing homes. He died on September 4, 1976.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Martin Kamin Collection is comprised of art, autographs, clippings, correspondence, memorabilia, Photographs, Printed naterial, subject files, and writings. Some of the material may have been part of the stock of the Kamin Dance Bookshop.
Art consists of costume and set design drawings and reference material as well as original prints by Mahlon Blaine, Carlos Merida, and several notable photographers, a self-portrait by Enrico Caruso, a Marie Taglioni paper doll, and a few other items.
Autographs contains the signatures of many well-known figures in the arts, including Prokofieff, Villa-Lobos, de Falla, and Stravinski.
Clippings consists of items about the Kamins and their bookshop as well as pieces on various dancers.
Correspondence includes both letters to and from the Kamins as well as letters collected by the Kamins. Correspondents in the former category encompass actors, authors, choreographers, composers, dancers and dance critics, including Jacques Bense, Konrad Bercovici, Evelyn Cournand (Anna Galina), Alexandra Danilova, Friderica Derra de Moroda, Anton "Pat" Dolin, Katherine Dunham, Martha Graham, Langston Hughes, Michel Licht, Alicia Markova, Peter Neagoe, Romola Nijinsky, Sydor Rey, Tomaz Ribas, Maurice Sandoz, Ted Shawn, Mia Slavenska, Walter Toscanini, Tamara Toumanova, Elisabeth Twysden, John Vassos, Lynd Ward, and Jacqueline and Robert de Warren. Correspondents in the latter category include a wide range of notables in the field of dance; one of the oldest items in this series (1832) is from Paul Taglioni, father and teacher of Marie Taglioni, the first ballerina to dance on en pointe before the days of toe-stiffened ballet slippers.
Memorabilia includes Sally Kamin's academic records, Martin Kamin's Parisian address book, financial records, a few items of dance memorabilia (including one of Nijinsky's costumes), loose photographs and several photograph albums, and assorted printed material.
The collection contains a large number of Photographs of ballet companies (among them Ballet Russe, Diaghilev Ballet, Martha Graham Dance Company, and the San Francisco Ballet), individual dancers (Alexandra Danilova, Alicia Markova, Nijinsky, Moira Shearer, and others), and specific dances (including Bluebeard, Camille, Giselle, Princess Aurora, and Swan Lake), as well as conductors and choreographers.
Printed material contains concert programs, dance instruction material, dance notation material, items from the Kamin's Dance Bookshop, magazine and newspaper clippings, pamphlets on various dance-related subjects, posters and broadsides, a substantial number of programs and souvenir booklets spanning more than fifty years and numerous countries, and miscellaneous items.
Subject files includes dance-related bibliographies and lists, two scrapbooks of promotional material from the Kamin Dance Bookshop, items from Kamin Publishers, and assorted notes and clippings on Michel Licht, the Middle East, and a military newspaper that Martin produced during World War II.
Writings is subdivided into writings by Martin, probably by Martin, by Sally, and by others. Martin's writings include handwritten notebooks dating from his years in the Army during World War II, handwritten notes for something entitled "Rascals", and assorted notes and fragments on other topics. Material presumed to be by Martin, though it cannot be said for certain, includes essays on dance, politics, World War II, and other topics. Writings by Sally consist of a handwritten essay on D. H. Lawrence and assorted notes and fragments. Writings by others include several items by and about Adolf Bolm, extensive material relating to two books by Maurice Sandoz (including a large amount of correspondence with the author), typed excerpts from a variety of plays (possibly used by Sally when studying for a role), a proposal for a book on American politics, essays on a range of dance-related topics, and the complete typescript of Encyclopedie du Ballet by Fernando Reyna.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged alphabetically by name (correspondence and photographs), by topic (subject files and memorabilia), or by type and title (printed material and writings).
Related Material
has a number of collections relating to dance and drama. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Separated Material
Some items, including a very large number of books and several early libretti, have been removed from the collection and transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate these items.
Subject and Genre Headings
Dance and theatre; Publishing, printing and book arts; Anthony, Gordon.; Bercovici, Konrad, 1882-1961.; Blaine, Mahlon.; Bolm, Adolph, 1884-1951.; Bosco, Henri, 1888-1976.; Buckle, Richard.; Coton, A. V.; De Mille, Agnes.; Denoël, Jean.; Dolin, Anton, 1904-1983.; Evans, Mary Stewart.; Graham, Martha.; Gribble, Harry Wagstaff, b. 1896.; Harris, Marguerite Tjader, 1901-1986.; Haskell, Arnold L. (Arnold Lionel), 1903-1980.; Janković, Danica S.; Kamin, Martin.; Kamin, Sally Katz, 1894?-1968.; Kirstein, Lincoln, 1907-1996.; Le Chanois, Jean-Paul, 1909-1985.; Legrand, Edy, 1893-1970.; Leslie, Kenneth, 1892-1974.; Leslie, Serge.; Lilly, Joseph.; Markova, Alicia, Dame, 1910-2004.; Massaguer, Conrado Walter, 1889-1965.; Mérida, Carlos, 1891-1984.; Neagoe, Peter.; Nijinsky, Romola de Pulszky.; Nijinsky, Vaslaw, 1890-1950.; Page, Ruth, 1899-1991.; Raffé, W. G. (Walter George), 1888-; Russell, Henry Tosti.; St. Denis, Ruth, 1880-1968.; Sandoz, Maurice, 1892-1958.; Seldes, George, 1890-1995.; Shawn, Ted, 1891-1972.; Strate, Walter.; Thackray, Rupert Manfred.; Toscanini, Walter, 1898-1971.; Toumanova, Tamara, 1919-1996.; Twysden, A. E. (Aileen Elizabeth), 1891-; Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964.; Vassos, John, 1898-1985.; Ward, Lynd, 1905-1985.; Yarborough, Lavinia Williams.; Kamin Dance Bookshop.; Ballerinas -- Photographs.; Ballet -- History -- Sources.; Ballet companies.; Ballet companies -- Photographs.; Ballet dancers.; Ballet dancers -- Photographs.; Ballet dancing.; Ballet dancing -- Photographs.; Booksellers and bookselling -- United States.; Dance.; Dance -- Study and teaching.; Dancers.; Dancers -- Photographs.; Polish Americans.; Publishers and publishing.; Address books.; Announcements.; Articles.; Autographs.; Bibliographies.; Biographies.; Broadsides (notices); Clippings (information artifacts); Diaries.; Ephemera.; Greeting cards.; Manuscripts for publication.; Memorabilia.; Pamphlets.; Photographs.; Programs (documents); Scrapbooks.; Scripts (documents); Booksellers and bookselling.; Publishers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Some material gift of Martin Kamin.
Some material gift of Lyall Squair, 1970, 1987.
Some material gift of John S. Mayfield.
Other material, unspecified, 1961, 1965, 1971, 1980.
Inventory
- Art
  - Costume design, mixture of clippings, hand-colored prints, original watercolors and sketches by unknown artists, etc.; includes plates and covers from Les Icones d'Ohrid and Fresques Serbes du Moyen Age; 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Costume design (Oversize 1)
  - Dancers, mixture of clippings, pages from books and manuscripts, hand-colored prints, original watercolors and sketches by unknown artists, etc.; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Dancers, mixture of clippings, pages from books and manuscripts, hand-colored prints, original watercolors and sketches by unknown artists, etc.; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Original art
    - Paintings and prints by Mahlon Blaine, original painting and woodblock prints by the American book illustrator and painter; 7 items (Map-case 136)
    - Photographs prints, various artists, 6 items (Oversize 1)
      Matched set of six photographic prints on what appears to be Japanese tissue or similar; one each by Alvin Langdon Coburn, Alfred Stieglitz, Prescott Adamson, Joseph T. Keiley, Gertrude Käsebier, and Clarence H. White.
    - Prints by Carlos Mérida, lithographs of Native American costume and dance; 25 items (Map-case 136)
    - Sketches, "original pencil sketch by N.R. Annotated" and "Misc. originals McClurg Kraus Bisch"; 2 folders (Oversize 1)
    - Miscellaneous, "Religious Medieval · Martha Graham" collage by Muriel Schochen; small watercolor by Pueblo painter Awa Tsireh (Alfonso Roybal); painting of three Native American dancers by unidentified artist; 2 folders (Map-case 136)
  - Self portrait by Enrico Caruso, 1916 (Box 2)
  - Set design, clippings, pages from books, etc. (Box 2)
  - Taglioni (Marie) paper doll, doll with several outfits, pages uncut and appear to be hand-colored (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous
- Autographs
  - Miscellaneous, composers, musicians, writers, celebrities, etc.; 3 folders (Box 2)
- Clippings
  - About Kamins
    - About Martin, Apr 1961; undated (Box 2)
    - About Sally, 8 Jan 1944 (Box 2)
  - Ballet companies
    - Denishawn Dancers (Box 2)
  - Dancers
    - Danilova, Alexandra (Box 2)
    - Dolin, Anton (Box 2)
      See also Printed material: Programs and souvenir booklets: Markova and Dolin, below.
    - Duncan, Isadora (Box 2)
    - Fonteyn, Margot (Box 2)
    - Lichine, David (Box 2)
    - Markova, Alicia (Box 2)
    - Massine, Leonide (Box 2)
    - Pavlova, Anna (Box 3)
    - Toumanova, Tamara (Box 3)
    - Various (Box 3)
- Correspondence
  - Martin and Sally (wife), 1942-1946; undated; 6 folders (Box 3)
  - A. A. Wyn, 1953; publisher (Box 3)
  - Ambrose, Kay, 1945-1946 (Box 3)
  - Anthony, Gordon, 1942; 1946-1947 (Box 3)
  - Archives Internationales de la Dance, 1946-1947; Pierre Tugal (Box 3)
  - Armstrong, Ronald, See Writings by others: Armstrong, Ronald
  - A, miscellaneous, includes typescript of letter to Lina Abarbanel (Box 3)
  - Barzel, Ann, See Kirstein, Lincoln.
  - Bassett, Richard, 1945; 1947,; 1950,; undated (Box 4)
  - Beckelman, Moses, 1945-1949; 1952,; 1955 (Box 4)
  - Bense, Jacques, 1945; 1947-1948,; 1958 (Box 4)
    See also Correspondence of others: English letters.
  - Bercovici, Conrad, 1945; undated (Box 4)
  - Berkebile, Fred, 1954; undated (Box 4)
  - Black, Helen, 1946-1947; 1950 (Box 4)
  - Blitzstein, Marc, 1943; undated (Box 4)
  - Bolm, Beate (wife of Adolf), 1955 (Box 4)
  - Bosco, Henri, 1943; Revue Aguedal (Box 4)
  - Brennan, Don, 1943-1949; undated (Box 4)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC), 1962 (Box 4)
  - Buckle, Richard, 1946-1947; 1953-1955 (Box 4)
  - Bueding, Raya, 1946-1947; undated (Box 4)
  - Bundy, Gus, 1955; 1961,; 1965,; undated (Box 4)
  - B, miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Calvocoressi, Michel-Dmitri, 1940 (Box 4)
  - Caracciolo, Marella (Princess), 1961 (Box 4)
  - Chatwin, Kenneth C., 1945 (Box 4)
  - Clique, 1945; 1951,; 1969,; 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - Cope, Thomas Pym, 1947; 1959,; undated (Box 4)
  - Coton, A. V., 1946-1947; 1949 (Box 4)
  - Cournand, Evelyn (Anna Galina), 1960; 1962 (Box 4)
  - C, miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Dali, Salvador, 1956; printed invitation to dinner with the Dalis and Maurice Sandoz, "at which...an interesting announcement will be made concerning a joint artistic venture connected with the forthcoming wedding of Miss Grace Kelly and Prince Rainier III" (Box 4)
  - Dance Quarterly, 1954; includes letters from numerous notable people regarding invitations to contribute, subscriptions, etc. (Box 4)
  - Daniels, Diana, 1954-1957 (Box 4)
  - Danilova, Alexandra, 1948; 1958 (Box 4)
  - Dayal, Leela, 1955-1956; 1962,; undated (Box 4)
  - De Mille, Agnes, 1952; 1955,; 1961,; undated (Box 4)
  - Deakin, Natasha and Irving, 1948; 1954,; 1959,; undated (Box 4)
  - Dennis Dobson Ltd., 1945-1953 (Box 4)
  - Denoël, Jean, 1943-1945 (Box 4)
  - Derra de Moroda, Friderica, 1959; 1961 (Box 4)
  - DeWulff, Catalina W., 1958-1960 (Box 4)
  - Dolin, Anton ("Pat"), 1943-1959; undated (Box 4)
  - Dunham, Katherine, 1954 (Box 4)
  - D, miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - E. P. Dutton, 1954-1955; Sharon Banigan (Box 4)
  - Evans, Mary Stewart (Lady Evans), 1947-1973; undated; includes handwritten notes on her Orchesography (Box 4)
  - E, miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Farrar, Straus & Co., 1946 (Box 4)
  - Galina, Anna, See Cournand, Evelyn.
  - Finkel, Saul, 1945 (Box 5)
  - Franck, Dorothea S., 1973 (Box 5)
  - Fung (Chinese consul), undated (Box 5)
  - F, miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Gantt, Harry, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Girdwood, James, 1964; undated (Box 5)
  - Goldberg, Arthur J., 1949 (Box 5)
  - Gor (Grossman), Robert, 1950 (Box 5)
  - Goslar, Lotte, 1948 (Box 5)
  - Graham, Martha, 1947 (Box 5)
  - Grayson, James, 1943-1946; 1972-1973 (Box 5)
  - Gribble, Harry Wagstaff, 1949; typescript of play, "The Feast of St. James" by Gribble and John Proctor (Box 5)
  - Grolier Society, 1959-1960 (Box 5)
  - G, miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Habicht, Hermann, 1942-1948; 1959-1960,; undated (Box 5)
  - Haden-Guest, Peter, 1951 (Box 5)
  - Hall, Martin, 1947; 1950 (Box 5)
  - Harris, Lou and Vera, 1959-1960 (Box 5)
  - Harris, Marguerite Tjader, 1941; 1947 (Box 5)
  - Haskell, Arnold L., 1937; 1946-1947 (Box 5)
  - Hata, Toyokichi, 1954; 1959 (Box 5)
  - Hawthorn Books, 1953 (Box 5)
  - Hennessy, Jossleyn, 1947 (Box 5)
  - Highet, Gilbert (Oxford University Press), 1958-1959 (Box 5)
  - Hill & Wang, 1958-1959; request for Sally to review Pudovkin book (Box 5)
  - L'Hommedieu, Bart, 1943-1947; undated (Box 5)
  - Hudson, Rosario, undated; includes photograph of Anna Pavlova, taken at Hudson's home (Box 5)
  - Hughes, Langston, 1926 (Box 5)
  - Humphrey, Doris, 1948; regarding Guggenheim application (Box 5)
  - Jagendorf, Moritz, 1943; 1956,; undated (Box 5)
  - Jankovic, Danica S., 1953-1958; undated; includes outlines and typescripts of their material on Yugoslavian folk music and folk dance (Box 5)
  - J, miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Kingsley, Herbert, 1939; contains handwritten piece of music written for Kamins (Box 5)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1938-1942; 1946,; 1952,; undated; Ballet Caravan, Inc. (Box 5)
  - Knopf, Inc., 1949; 1953,; 1964 (Box 5)
  - Kramer [Kraemer?], Chris, 1942-1943; 1946,; 1950 (Box 5)
  - Krehel, Peter, 1945-1952; undated (Box 5)
  - Lawson, Jean, 1947 (Box 5)
  - Le Chanois, Jean-Paul, 1945-1952; 1958-1959,; undated (Box 5)
  - Legrand, Edy, 1943-1945; 1961-1965,; undated (Box 5)
  - Lee, Paul, 1943 (Box 5)
  - Leidy, Philip, 1941 (Box 5)
  - Lempertz, Thomas Q., 1961 (Box 5)
  - Leslie, Kenneth, 1943-1944; 1952-1955 (Box 5)
  - Leslie, Serge and Doris, 1954; 1958,; undated (Box 5)
  - Leyda, Jay, 1949 (Box 6)
  - Library of Congress, 1929; 1938-1960,; undated (Box 6)
  - Licht, Michel, 1948 (Box 6)
  - Lidji, Lena, 1947 (Box 6)
  - Lilly, Joseph, 1942-1949; undated (Box 6)
  - Littell, Ray S., 1959-1960 (Box 6)
  - Lloyd, Margaret, 1943-1948; undated (Box 6)
  - Love, Paul, 1950-1953 (Box 6)
  - L, miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Marc, Emile, 1946 (Box 6)
  - Markova, Alicia, 1942; 1947,; 1950,; 1973,; undated (Box 6)
  - Martin, Ben, 1944-1945 (Box 6)
  - Martin, John, 1943 (Box 6)
  - Massaguer, Conrado, 1959-1960 (Box 6)
  - Mayfield, John S., 1943-1944; 1948,; 1952,; 1965,; 1967,; 1969,; 1973,; undated (Box 6)
  - Mehdi, [Mohammad T. ?], 1972 (Box 6)
  - Meister, Guido, 1959; undated (Box 6)
  - de Monbrison, Arnaud [?], 1943; undated (Box 6)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1914 (Box 6)
  - M, miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Nagle, Carl, 1963-1964; undated (Box 6)
  - Neagoe, Peter, 1950; 1958,; undated; about his books published by Kamin; includes book reviews, press releases, clippings, author photos (Box 6)
  - Neagoe, Peter and Anna, 1958-1962; 1973,; undated; letters to and from the Kamins (Box 6)
  - New York Public Library, 1946; 1961 (Box 6)
  - Nijinska, Romola (wife of Vaslav Nijinsky), 1950-1963; 1973,; undated; correspondence; annotated clippings (Box 6)
  - N, miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Orloff, N. [Nicholas?], 1946 (Box 7)
  - Oukrainsky, Serge, 1961 (Box 7)
  - O, miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Page, Ruth, 1948 (Box 7)
  - Passport office, 1934-1935; 1945-1946 (Box 7)
  - Pavelic, Ante, 1943; undated (Box 7)
  - Pearl [may be first or last name, not clear], 1940s (Box 7)
  - Porter, Russ ( New York Times), 1943; 1948,; undated (Box 7)
  - Prendergast, A. H. D., 1907-1909; letters to Prendergast from several different people, none of them Kamin (Box 7)
  - Prilipp, Beda, 1952-1953 (Box 7)
  - Putnam & Company, 1942 (Box 7)
  - P, miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Raffe, Walter George R., 1946; 1948,; 1955 (Box 7)
  - Random House, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Rene, Natalia, 1957-1960 (Box 7)
  - Rey, Sydor, 1941; 1965-1966,; 1973 (Box 7)
  - Ribas, Tomaz, 1963 (Box 7)
    See also Writings: By Kamin, probably: Dance.
  - Russell, Henry Tosti, 1958-1960; undated; includes reprint, "Welcome to Portugal, Maurice Sandoz" (Box 7)
  - Q-R, miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Sadoul, Georges, undated (Box 7)
  - Sakowicz, Gabriela, 1946 (Box 7)
  - Sandoz, Maurice, See Writings by others: Armstrong, Ronald; Writings by others: Sandoz, Maurice
  - Schonberg, Harriett, 1957-1963 (Box 7)
  - Seidel, Winifred, 1947 (Box 7)
  - Seldes, George, 1940; 1942,; undated (Box 7)
    See also Writings: By others: Seldes, George.
  - Selznick, David O., 1956 (Box 7)
  - Shawn, Ted, 1947-1961; undated (Box 7)
    See also Photographs: Albums: [Album 1].
  - Silbermann, Alphons, 1948-1950 (Box 7)
  - Slavenska, Mia, 1940; 1946,; undated (Box 7)
  - Sorrell, Walter, 1948-1950 (Box 7)
  - Soudeikine, Serge, 1941 (Box 7)
  - Sterling, David, 1943-1944; undated (Box 7)
  - Strate, Walter, 1954-1957; undated (Box 7)
  - Stuart Press, 1959-1960; undated (Box 7)
  - S, miscellaneous, includes Christmas card from State Opera Ballet of Prague, signed by all members (Box 7)
  - Thackray, Rupert W., 1960; most is with Mark Paterson and Company Ltd. about Thackray's book (Box 7)
  - Toscanini, Walter, 1954-1955 (Box 7)
  - Totten, Vivian, 1971-1973; undated (Box 7)
  - Toumanova, Tamara, undated; includes photograph (Box 7)
  - Trosch, Evelyn and Erving, 1951-1952; undated (Box 7)
  - Tuttle, Frank W., 1948 (Box 7)
  - Twysden, Elisabeth (A.E.), 1947-1957; about her book on Alicia Markova (Box 8)
  - Twysden, Elisabeth (A.E.), 1942-1958; undated; to and from the Kamins (Box 8)
  - T, miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - United Nations Rehabilitation and Relief Agency (UNRRA), 1944-1948 (Box 8)
  - U, miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Van Vechten, Carl, 1942-1943; 1953,; undated; includes several postcards with his own photographs (Box 8)
  - Vassos, John, 1943-1945; undated; includes sketches, letter to Maurice Sandoz (Box 8)
    See also Memorabilia: Clippings.
  - Vermilye, Ted and Alice, 1950-1952 (Box 8)
    See also Writings by others: Vermilye, Theodore.
  - Vernon, Norman, 1942 (Box 8)
  - V, miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Ward, Lynd, 1935; 1942 (Box 8)
  - de Warren, Robert and Jacqueline, 1965; 1973 (Box 8)
    See also Writings: By others: de Warren, Robert and Jacqueline.
  - Watson, Harry S., 1945 (Box 8)
  - Weiner, Beryl (Rod Geiger Productions), 1948; 1952,; 1957 (Box 8)
  - White, Walter, 1944-1948; includes a 5-page typescript, possibly from White's memoirs, that talks about Kamin
  - W, miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Yarborough, Lavinia Williams, 1962-1963 (Box 8)
  - Y-Z, miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Unidentified, 1943-1945; 1973,; undated; Jimmy, Anka, Bronka; possibly relatives? (Box 8)
  - Unidentified, A-Z by first name (Box 8)
  - Unidentified, no name at all or completely illegible; includes 1951 letter from Sally detailing health and other issues (Box 8)
  - Correspondence/writings of others
    These items are to and from someone other than the Kamins. The majority of these items are numbered, but no list of or key to these numbers has been found. It is possible that these items were part of the stock of dance-related memorabilia bought and sold at the Kamins' store.
    - "Ballabile e variazioni Serpentina", 18th century; handwritten manuscript in Italian with diagrams in later binding, title page has the name "Egidia" (Box 8)
    - "Country dance letters", 1789; handwritten, apparently fragments of larger document or book (Box 8)
    - Greeting and postcards, 1925-1957 (Box 8)
    - English letters, 1853-1956; includes letters to and/or from Jacques Bense, Eugene Berman, Adolf and Beate Bolm, Jeanette Derby, Anton Dolin, Adeline Genee-Isitt, Doris Humphrey, Maria Ouspenskaya, and Igor Stravinsky (Box 9)
    - Foreign language letters (1), 1832-1962; letters in French, German, Greek, Hungarian, Russian, other languages; 5 folders (Box 9)
    - Foreign language letters (2), 1807-1962; letters in French, German, Greek, Russian, other languages (Box 10)
- Memorabilia
  - Academics (Sally), copies of transcripts, letters of recommendation, degree credits, National Dance League Award, etc. (Box 10)
  - Address books (Box 10)
  - Biographical material, biographical sketches, resumés, Martin's military record, tribute by Dorothea Franck, etc. (Box 10)
  - Clippings, includes article on John Vassos with photo (Box 10)
  - Dance memorabilia (Oversize 8)
    Harlequin-patterned leotard worn by Nijinsky, showing multiple repairs; tie and small mother-of-pearl/malachite box (broken), with note saying they belonged to Nijinsky; unidentified partial costume, appears to be part of belly-dancer skirt
  - Fellowship information, relating to Sally Kamin's Guggenheim application (Box 10)
  - Financial
    - Bank statements (Box 10)
    - Medical (Box 10)
    - Miscellany (Box 10)
  - Marriage certificate (copy) (Box 10)
  - Photographs
    - Martin Kamin (Box 10)
    - Sally Kamin (Sarah Nikov), 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Photo album (1), 1914-1916; oblong, plain cover; candid photos (Oversize 3)
    - Photo album (2), 1914-1916; rectangular, "Photographs" printed on cover; candid photos (Oversize 3)